Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're looking for a new job.
我是Catherine，今天我们正在找新工作。
That's right, we are looking for a new job and so we're bringing you this great lesson
没错，我们正在找新工作，所以为大家带来了这节精彩的课程。
where we're going to teach you in English a lot of terms related with looking for a
在这节课里，我们会教大家很多与找工作相关的英语词汇。
job or things like a resume, cover letter.
比如简历、求职信之类的。
So before we get into that, why don't we take a look at a word that we have in Vocabulary
在进入正题之前，我们先来看看词汇预览里的一个词。
Preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
So this is actually the name of a job.
这其实是一个职位名称。
It's a position.
它是一个岗位。
It's a gas station attendant.
加油站服务员。
Okay, a gas station attendant.
好的，加油站服务员。
Now we know what a gas station is, right?
我们都知道加油站是什么，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's a place where you go to fill your car with gas.
就是你去给车加油的地方。
Okay.
好的。
So an attendant at a gas station, what does he do?
那么加油站的服务员是做什么的呢？
He or she is a person who will help you put the gas in your car.
他或她会帮你给车加油。
So an attendant is someone who is almost like an assistant or a helper.
所以服务员就像是助手或帮手一样的人。
You can have a bathroom attendant, someone who gives you a towel after you wash your
你可以雇一个洗手间服务员，就是那种在你洗完手后递毛巾的人。
hands.
手。
I've seen those in the fancy restaurants.
我在高档餐厅见过那种。
Yeah, so gas station attendant.
对，就像加油站服务员一样。
Alright, so why don't we take a look now at our dialogue.
好了，那我们现在来看看对话吧。
Let's listen to it for the first time and we'll be back in a bit.
我们第一次听一下，一会儿再回来。
Woohoo!
哇哦！
This just might be the start of the rest of my life.
这可能是我余生的开始。
What happened?
发生什么事了？
I'm in the market for a job.
我正在找工作。
I went on a website with hundreds of job listings in the area and browsed through them until
我上了一个网站，上面有本地几百个职位列表，我浏览了一遍，直到
I got the names of a few employers I would like to work for.
我找到了几个我想为之工作的雇主名字。
I have the resume I wrote for English class last month and a cover letter will be a piece
我有上个月为英语课写的简历，写求职信对我来说是小菜一碟。
of cake to write.
写起来。
I've even done my research and found the names of the managers so I can address the letters
我甚至做了调查，找到了经理的名字，这样我就可以在信上
personally.
直接称呼他们。
And you know, I can be charming in interviews.
而且你知道，我在面试中可以很有魅力。
Goodbye my penniless days, hello salary and a career.
再见了我穷困的日子，你好薪水和事业。
Ben, we're 15.
本，我们才15岁。
What kind of job are you looking for?
你在找什么样的工作？
Oh, just for a position as a gas station attendant.
哦，只是应聘一个加油站服务员的工作。
You know, starting at a simple lowly job just like all the greats before they made it big
你知道，从一份简单卑微的工作开始，就像所有那些成名前的大人物一样。
in the world.
在这个世界上。
Uh huh.
嗯哼。
But I'm just in it for the money, right?
但我只是为了钱，对吧？
How else am I going to be able to afford to keep taking Angela to the movies?
不然我怎么能负担得起继续带安吉拉去看电影呢？
Besides, I love the smell of gasoline.
再说了，我喜欢汽油的味道。
Don't you?
你不喜欢吗？
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now you're probably wondering what those words meant.
所以现在你可能在想那些词是什么意思。
So why don't we take a look at a couple of them in Language Takeaway.
那我们不如在“语言要点”环节看看其中几个。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
The first phrase we have today is one that's very important when you're looking for a job.
我们今天第一个短语在找工作时非常重要。
It's called job listing or job listings here.
它叫做“职位列表”或“招聘列表”。
Okay, job listings.
好的，职位列表。
And this is really common before the internet existed.
这在互联网出现之前非常常见。
You would have the listings in your local newspaper, right?
你会在当地报纸上看到这些列表，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
In the movies, you always had the person sitting with the newspaper circling the potential
在电影里，你总能看到有人拿着报纸圈出潜在的。
jobs.
工作。
Right, with a red marker.
对，用红色记号笔。
Exactly.
没错。
But now that we have the internet, you have lots of websites that have job listings.
但现在有了互联网，有很多网站提供职位列表。
And so a job listing is literally a list of jobs that are available.
所以职位列表就是一份可供选择的职位清单。
Okay.
好的。
So you look through the job listings.
你浏览职位列表。
Maybe you found one that's interesting.
也许你找到了一个感兴趣的。
There's an email address.
上面有个邮箱地址。
So what do they ask for?
那他们要你做什么？
They ask you to send in your resume.
他们让你发送简历。
Okay.
好的。
A resume is very important when you're looking for a job.
找工作时，简历非常重要。
It's a document.
这是一份文件。
It's a piece of paper that tells someone all of the work that you've done before, your
它是一张纸，告诉别人你之前做过的工作、
job experiences, and it tells them where you went to school and what your qualifications
工作经历，还告诉他们你上过什么学校以及你的资格
are.
是什么。
So it's a summary of your work life.
所以它是你工作生涯的总结。
Okay.
好的。
And that's why it's called a resume, right?
这就是为什么它叫简历，对吧？
It's pretty much a summary of your work life, as you say.
正如你所说，它基本上是你工作生涯的总结。
That's right.
没错。
And a different one, sometimes people use this, is a CV, curriculum vitae, and that's
另一种不同的说法，有时人们会用这个，就是 CV，curriculum vitae，那是
an academic summary of your life.
你人生的学术总结。
So you have the work summary and the study summary.
所以你有工作总结和学习总结。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So if you send in your resume, what's recommended is that you attach it with a cover letter.
所以如果你寄出简历，建议你附上一封求职信。
Okay.
好的。
Well, cover letter, you know the word letter.
嗯，求职信，你知道“信”这个词。
It's something that you write to somebody else.
这是你写给别人的东西。
But a cover letter is like a cover for your resume.
但求职信就像是你简历的封面。
It's a letter where you explain to the future boss or future employer what exactly you want
这是一封信，你在信中向未来的老板或未来雇主解释你到底想要什么，
and how this job is going to help you get it.
以及这份工作如何帮助你实现它。
Okay.
好的。
So that's basically a small little introduction to yourself, right?
所以这基本上是一个简短的个人介绍，对吧？
Before they read your resume, who you are, what you're looking for, maybe very quickly.
在他们读你的简历之前，你是谁，你在找什么，可能非常简短。
Exactly.
正是。
So you can say, Hi, my name is Catherine.
所以你可以说，嗨，我叫凯瑟琳。
I'm very motivated and excited to have the opportunity to talk to you about why I'm a
我非常有动力，也很兴奋有机会和你谈谈为什么我是一个
skilled employee and why I will benefit your company.
有技能的员工，以及为什么我会让你的公司受益。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好的。
So you've sent in your resume and your cover letter.
所以你已经寄出了你的简历和求职信。
And well, maybe you're looking to get into a career as a gas station attendant.
嗯，也许你想进入加油站服务员这个职业。
So what's the difference between job and career?
那么工作和职业有什么区别？
Okay.
好的。
And this is very interesting because in many languages, there is a similar word, which
这很有趣，因为在很多语言中，有一个类似的词，
for example, in Spanish is carrera, right?
比如在西班牙语中是 carrera，对吧？
And that means like a profession.
那意味着一种职业。
So many people translate it literally as career, but it's not the right word.
所以很多人直译成 career，但这不是正确的词。
What is a career?
什么是 career？
A career I think of as a long term goal.
我认为 career 是一个长期目标。
A career is your profession.
Career 是你的职业。
It's the name you give yourself.
是你给自己的称号。
But a job is a position in a company from one time to another.
但 job 是公司里从一段时间到另一段时间的一个职位。
So for example, my job here is host of EnglishPod.
所以例如，我的工作这里是 EnglishPod 的主持人。
But maybe in the future, I will have a media career.
但也许将来，我会有一个媒体 career。
That means that my job or jobs will have to do with this profession.
这意味着我的工作或工作们将与这个职业有关。
It's kind of a bigger thing, a longer thing.
这是一个更大的事情，更长久的事情。
So maybe you can think of it this way.
所以也许你可以这样想。
A career is like, as you say, bigger picture, like the macro category, right?
Career 就像，如你所说，更大的画面，像宏观类别，对吧？
You're into media and television, for example.
你从事媒体和电视，例如。
And your job specifically is a podcast host.
而你的具体工作是一个播客主持人。
But in the future, maybe I want to have a different job in this career and move into
但将来，也许我想在这个 career 中有一个不同的工作，并进入
production and be a TV producer.
制作领域，成为一名电视制片人。
So that's a part of my career path.
所以那是我 career 路径的一部分。
I can move forward.
我可以向前发展。
So career is very important word.
所以 career 是一个非常重要的词。
All right.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a couple of great words.
所以我们看了一些很棒的词。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
我们为什么不听一遍我们的对话，然后我们一会儿回来。
I've even done my research and found the names of the managers so I can address the
我甚至做了研究，找到了经理们的名字，这样我就可以亲自
letters personally.
写信给他们。
And you know, I can be charming in interviews.
而且你知道，我在面试中可以很有魅力。
Goodbye my penniless days.
再见，我穷困的日子。
Hello salary and a career.
你好，薪水和 career。
Ben, we're 15.
本，我们才15岁。
What kind of job are you looking for?
你在找什么样的工作？
Oh, just for a position as a gas station attendant.
哦，只是一个加油站服务员的职位。
You know, starting at a simple lowly job, just like all the greats before they made
你知道，从一份简单卑微的工作开始，就像所有伟人在他们
it big in the world.
在世界上成功之前一样。
But I'm just in it for the money, right?
但我只是为了钱，对吧？
How else am I going to be able to afford to keep taking Angela to the movies?
不然我怎么负担得起继续带安吉拉去看电影？
Besides, I love the smell of gasoline.
而且，我喜欢汽油的味道。
Don't you?
你不喜欢吗？
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now we have lined up for you three key phrases that we found in this dialogue.
所以现在我们为你准备了我们在对话中找到的三个关键短语。
So let's take a look at those now in Fluency Builder.
让我们现在在 Fluency Builder 中看看它们。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
This first one's a great phrase.
第一个是一个很棒的短语。
It's going to make you sound very fluent in English if you use it.
如果你用它，会让你听起来英语很流利。
We say in the market for.
我们说 in the market for。
I'm in the market for a new job.
我正在找一份新工作。
All right.
好的。
So this person is looking for a new job.
所以这个人在找一份新工作。
He is in the market for.
他正在寻找。
I could also say, I'm in the market for a new house.
我也可以说，我正在找一所新房子。
Marco, do you know any good real estate agents?
马可，你认识好的房地产经纪人吗？
So what does that mean if you say I'm in the market for a new job or you're in the market
所以如果你说我在找新工作或你在找，那是什么意思？
for a new house?
是为了找新房子吗？
I am right now actively looking for this thing.
我现在正在积极寻找这个东西。
I really want one.
我真的很想要一个。
You're available.
你有空。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So I'm in the market for a new job.
所以我现在正在找工作。
I'm in the market for a new car.
我正在找新车。
It means the market is the marketplace.
它的意思是市场就是交易场所。
Right, right.
对，对。
And this sometimes you could see it related in movies.
有时候你可以在电影里看到这个说法。
For example, they say if a person gets married, they are no longer in the market.
比如，他们说如果一个人结婚了，他们就不再是“在市场上”了。
I'm in the market for a husband.
我正在找老公。
Right.
对。
Do you know any nice guys?
你认识什么好男人吗？
All right.
好吧。
So you're in the market.
所以你在市场上。
You're looking for a job.
你在找工作。
And well, if you're qualified, it will be a piece of cake to find a new job.
嗯，如果你有资格，找新工作会是小菜一碟。
Isn't this a delicious phrase?
这个短语是不是很美味？
So piece of cake, you think what does cake have to do with anything?
小菜一碟，你觉得蛋糕跟这事儿有什么关系？
Well, cake, this is a way to say something is easy.
嗯，蛋糕，这是一种表示某事很容易的说法。
Okay, so it's really easy.
好的，所以就是真的很简单。
This often happens in our office actually, because you and I understand computers, but
这在我们办公室其实经常发生，因为你我懂电脑，但是
we work with someone who has a hard time with computers.
我们跟一个不太会用电脑的人一起工作。
And she's like, oh, it doesn't work.
她就会说，哦，它坏了。
And we're like, it's a piece of cake.
我们就会说，这很简单。
It's a piece of cake.
小菜一碟。
It's so easy.
太容易了。
Why is this hard?
这有什么难的？
So a piece of cake is a way to say something simple.
所以“小菜一碟”是一种表示某事简单的说法。
And it's a very, very, very common phrase.
而且这是一个非常非常常见的短语。
You'll hear it all the time.
你会经常听到。
A piece of cake, don't worry about it.
小菜一碟，别担心。
Piece of cake.
小菜一碟。
Hey, can you help me out with this thing?
嘿，你能帮我处理一下这个吗？
Sure, it's a piece of cake.
当然，小菜一碟。
All right.
好的。
And for our last phrase, he was talking about his position as a gas attendant.
至于我们最后一个短语，他谈到自己作为加油站服务员的工作。
And he said, well, you know, all the greats, all the famous people, they started somewhere
他说，嗯，你知道，所有的大人物，所有名人，他们都是从某个地方起步的。
before they made it big.
在他们成功之前。
What does he mean with they made it big?
他说的“made it big”是什么意思？
Well, the phrase to make it big or in here in the past tense, made it big, means to be
嗯，“make it big”这个短语，或者这里用的过去式“made it big”，意思是
successful.
成功。
So we're talking about, for example, Albert Einstein.
所以我们是在说，比如阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦。
Albert Einstein worked in the patent office in a clue.
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦曾在专利局工作，在一个小办公室里。
He was a clerk in Europe.
他在欧洲当过职员。
And you know, that's not a very impressive job, but it was a job.
你知道，那不是什么了不起的工作，但好歹是份工作。
And he made it big later on as a physicist.
后来他作为物理学家取得了巨大成功。
And so to make it big is to succeed, to become famous or successful or important.
所以“make it big”就是成功，变得出名、成功或重要。
Right.
对。
Or sometimes people say, yeah, I made it.
或者有时人们会说，是的，我成功了。
I made it big or I made it in my life.
我大获成功，或者我这一生成功了。
And that means that you were successful.
那意味着你成功了。
Or this product is going to make it big.
或者这个产品会大获成功。
It's going to be really successful.
它会非常成功。
Yeah, that's good.
嗯，不错。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a key phrase to make it or to make it big.
所以这是一个关键短语：“make it”或“make it big”。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back in a little bit.
我们最后再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Woohoo!
哇呼！
This just might be the start of the rest of my life.
这也许就是我余生的开端。
What happened?
发生什么事了？
I'm in the market for a job.
我正在找工作。
I went on a website with hundreds of job listings in the area and browsed through them until
我上了一个网站，上面有几百个本地职位列表，我浏览了一遍，直到
I got the names of a few employers I would like to work for.
找到了几个我想为之工作的雇主名字。
I have the resume I wrote for English class last month and a cover letter will be a piece
我有上个月英语课写的简历，写一封求职信简直是小菜一碟。
of cake to write.
写起来易如反掌。
I've even done my research and found the names of the managers so I can address the letters
我甚至做了功课，找到了经理的名字，这样我就能亲自
personally.
在信上称呼他们。
And you know, I can be charming in interviews.
而且你知道，我在面试时能表现得很有魅力。
Goodbye my penniless days.
再见，我身无分文的日子。
Hello salary and a career.
你好，薪水和事业。
Ben, we're 15.
本，我们才15岁。
What kind of job are you looking for?
你在找什么样的工作？
Oh, just for a position as a gas station attendant.
哦，就找个加油站服务员之类的职位。
You know, starting at a simple lowly job just like all the greats before they made it big
你知道，就像所有那些在世界上功成名就的大人物一样，从一份简单卑微的工作开始，
in the world.
然后才出人头地。
Uh huh.
嗯哼。
But I'm just in it for the money, right?
但我只是为了钱，对吧？
How else am I going to be able to afford to keep taking Angela to the movies?
不然我怎么能负担得起继续带安吉拉去看电影呢？
Besides, I love the smell of gasoline.
再说了，我喜欢汽油的味道。
Don't you?
你不喜欢吗？
All right, so talking about jobs, now I noticed something that in the United States, unlike
好吧，说到工作，我注意到在美国，和
many other countries, there are no gas station attendants anymore.
很多其他国家不同，现在已经没有加油站服务员了。
There are.
还是有的。
Touche.
说得好。
There are actually a lot of gas station attendants in New Jersey because it's the law that you
实际上新泽西州还有很多加油站服务员，因为法律规定你
cannot pump your own gas.
不能自己加油。
You cannot put gas in your own car.
你不能自己给车加油。
Why is that?
为什么？
It's a way for the New Jersey government to increase the amount of jobs in the states.
这是新泽西州政府增加州内就业岗位的一种方式。
So to create jobs, they made gas station attendants.
所以为了创造就业，他们设立了加油站服务员这个岗位。
Oh wow.
哦，哇。
Yeah, I've noticed in some states, for example, you just go up to the pump and if you have
是啊，我注意到在一些州，比如你直接去加油机，如果你有
your credit card, you put in your credit card and you pump your own gas.
信用卡，插进去就能自己加油。
And apparently it also has to do with health issues because people who are working in gas
而且显然这还跟健康问题有关，因为在加油站工作的人
stations tend to have serious health problems later on.
后来往往会有严重的健康问题。
I mean, you're inhaling all these gases from the gasoline.
我是说，你一直在吸入汽油里的这些气体。
That's right.
没错。
It's very unhealthy.
这非常不健康。
And I think that's also very dangerous in some places because gas stations are often
而且我认为在某些地方这也非常危险，因为加油站通常
robbed because there's only one person and no security sometimes.
被抢是因为有时候只有一个人，而且没有安保措施。
So there are some negative parts of being a gas station attendant.
所以说，当加油站服务员也有一些不好的地方。
But if it's a job and you need a job, it's probably a good one.
但如果这是一份工作，而且你需要一份工作，那它很可能是个好工作。
Yeah, no, true.
嗯，对，确实。
I actually, I remember seeing Back to the Future when in the 50s, you would pull up
实际上，我记得看过《回到未来》，在50年代，你会把车停到
to a gas station, somebody would check your tire pressure, they would check your oil and
去加油站时，会有人帮你检查胎压、检查机油。
they would clean your windows and it's just like full service when you pulled up to a
他们会帮你擦车窗，就像你开车到加油站时享受的全套服务一样。
gas station.
加油站。
They might even buy you a beer.
他们甚至可能请你喝杯啤酒。
Alright, so it's really interesting about these positions.
好的，这些职位真的很有意思。
I imagine that in other places, some job positions that maybe we would find a little bit strange
我想在别的地方，有些职位我们可能会觉得有点奇怪。
or uncommon.
或者不常见的。
Absolutely.
当然。
And I encourage everyone today, this is your homework, tell us on EnglishPod.com what is
今天我要鼓励大家，这是你们的作业，在EnglishPod.com上告诉我们，什么是
your job and what's your career.
你的工作是什么？你的职业是什么？
What's your job and what's your career.
你的工作是什么，你的职业又是什么。
So what's the career you would like to have in the future.
那么，你未来想从事什么职业呢？
Very good.
很好。
Alright, so we'll see you guys there.
好的，那我们到时候见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Make sure to subscribe to olur Why.
记得订阅我们的“为什么”频道。